Guide to the Kenneth Hubbard Collection of Political Campaign Ephemera, 1880-2012 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kenneth Hubbard Collection of Political Campaign Ephemera 1880-2012 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hubbard, Kenneth
2.2 linear feet Extent: 664 Items
Collector of campaign memorabilia. The Kenneth Hubbard Collection of Political Campaign Ephemera consists of memorabilia from almost every U.S. presidential campaign from 1880 to 2012, chiefly relating to the Democratic and Republican parties. Buttons make up most of the items, but there are also lapel pins and other artifacts. Arranged by year and candidate name.
hubbardkenneth
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Kenneth Hubbard Collection of Political Campaign Ephemera was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2006.
Collection Overview
The Kenneth Hubbard Collection of Political Campaign Ephemera consists of memorabilia from almost every U.S. presidential campaign from 1880 to 2012, chiefly relating to the Democratic and Republican parties. Buttons make up most of the items, but there are also lapel pins and other artifacts. Arranged by year and candidate name.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Democratic Party (U.S.)--History; Republican Party (U.S.)--History; Elections -- United States -- History; Political campaigns -- United States -- History; Political parties -- United States -- History; Presidential candidates -- United States; Presidents -- United States -- Election; Buttons (information artifacts).; Memorabilia
Related Material
The David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library holds thousands of bound pamphlets and manuscript collections relating to United States elections, as well as archival collections focused on individual political figures, particularly in the state of North Carolina, and Durham, Orange, and Wake counties. In addition, the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library holds these collections containing materials closely related to or complementing the collection described in this finding aid:
Collection of U.S. Political Campaign Materials, 1840-2000 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Richard Bentley Collection of Presidential Campaign Memorabilia, 1961-1992
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Richard E. McDonald Political Campaign Collection, undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Contents of Collection
- Political Campaign Ephemera, 1880-2012 and undated, (4 boxes)
  - 1880, Garfield, James (Box 1)
  - 1888, Harrison, Benjamin
  - 1896, McKinley, William
  - 1928, Hoover, Herbert
  - 1932-1944, Roosevelt, Franklin Delano
  - 1940, Wilkie, Wendell
  - 1948, Dewey, Thomas
  - 1952-1956, Eisenhower, Dwight
  - 1952-1960, Stevenson, Adlai
  - 1960, Kennedy, John F.
  - 1960-1972, Nixon, Richard
  - 1964:
    - Goldwater, Barry
    - Johnson, Lyndon B.
    - Lodge Jr., Henry Cabot
  - 1968:
    - Humphrey, Hubert
    - Kennedy, Robert
    - Paulsen, Pat
    - Poor People's Campaign
    - Rockefeller, Nelson
  - 1972:
    - McCarthy, Eugene
    - McGovern, George
    - Muskie, Ed
  - 1980, Carter, Jimmy
  - 1980-1984, Reagan, Ronald
  - 1988, Bush, George
  - 2000-2004, Bush, George
  - 2004:
    - Kerry, John
    - Dean, Howard
    - Nader, Ralph
  - Undated:
    - "Abe"
    - Miniature eyeglasses (Roosevelt, Theodore?)
    - Republican Party elephant
    - Miscellaneous
    - Senior Power for the President
    - Young Voters for the President
  - 1952-1956, Eisenhower, Dwight (Box 2)
  - 1952-1960, Stevenson, Adlai
  - 1960, Kennedy, John F.
  - 1960-1972, Nixon, Richard
  - 1964:
    - Goldwater, Barry
    - Johnson, Lyndon B.
  - 1968, Rockefeller, Nelson
  - 1972, McGovern, George
  - 2000-2004, Bush, George
  - 2004, Kerry, John
  - 2012: (Box 3-4)
    - Obama, Barack
    - Romney, Mitt